Finding aid to Alumnae College Records, 1933-2001 CA.MS.00306
Smith College Archives
Alumnae College records
1933-2001
Smith College Archives
Alumnae College
CA.MS.00306
1.25 linear feet (3 containers)
The Alumnae College records document an event that takes place during commencement and includes brochures, lecture notes, speeches, reading lists, memos, correspondence, minutes, schedules, press releases, newspaper clippings, and photographs.
Biographical / Historical
Alumnae College, which began in 1933, is an event which takes place during Commencement week. It takes the form of a series of lectures given by professors on topics which, historically, have ranged from discussions of culture and society in Germany to "The Garden: Art and Nature." Smith Alumnae of all ages attend Alumnae College, which allows these alumnae to engage in learning with each other in a very unique way, focusing on one particular topic, and discussing it with alumnae from different classes. In the early years of the program, Alumnae College went on for an entire week, but the recent sessions have lasted only a day or two. Though the collection only contains records through 2001, Alumnae College continues to offer classes.
Scope and Contents
The Alumnae College records contain materials from nearly every year that Alumnae College has taken place. The bulk of the material is from 1933 to the mid-1950s, consisting of brochures, schedules, lecture notes, speeches, press releases, newspaper clippings, and photographs, except for the World War II years. From the 1950s onward, the records are less complete, and consist mostly of brochures, with some photographs, lecture notes, and other miscellanea. The records from 1941 and 1942 are of special interest as they also contain pamphlets and other materials relating to World War II.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Alumnae College Records were obtained from the Smith College Alumnae Association.
Alumnae College
- Britain, 1933 (Box 1308, Folder 1)
- Germany, 1934 (Box 1308, Folder 2)
- France, 1935 (Box 1308, Folder 3)
- United States, 1936 (Box 1308, Folder 4)
- The Mediterranean, 1937 (Box 1308, Folder 5)
- The Renaissance, 1938 (Box 1308, Folder 6)
- The Liberal Tradition, 1939 (Box 1308, Folder 7)
- These Last Fifty Years in the United States, 1940 (Box 1308, Folder 8)
- The Americas, 1941 (Box 1309, Folder 1)
- Toward World Order, 1942 (Box 1309, Folder 2)
- Toward World Order, 1942 (Box 1309, Folder 3)
- State of the Nation, 1946 (Box 1309, Folder 4)
- The Problem of Liberty Today, 1947 (Box 1309, Folder 5)
- These Last Fifty Years in the United States, 1948 (Box 1309, Folder 6)
- Horizon-1949 (Box 1309, Folder 7)
- Twentieth Century Revolutions: Reality or Illusion?, 1950 (Box 1309, Folder 8)
- Here and Now, 1951 (Box 1309, Folder 9)
- Today's Frontiers: A Challenge to the Individual, 1952 (Box 1309, Folder 10)
- India: Traditions in a Modern Context, 1953 (Box 1309, Folder 11)
- Africa South of the Sahara, 1954 (Box 1309, Folder 12)
- Aspects of Understanding, 1955 (Box 1309, Folder 13)
- The Risks of Freedom, 1956 (Box 1309, Folder 14)
- Values and Conformity, 1957 (Box 1309, Folder 15)
- The Far East: Understandings and the American Role, 1958 (Box 1309, Folder 16)
- Critical Issues: 1959 (Box 1309, Folder 17)
- Symposium on Existentialism, 1960 (Box 1310, Folder 1)
- The Two Cultures, 1961 (Box 1310, Folder 2)
- Modern Images of Man and Society, 1962 (Box 1310, Folder 3)
- The City, 1963 (Box 1310, Folder 4)
- Minorities in the New World, 1964 (Box 1310, Folder 5)
- Challenges to Reason, 1965 (Box 1310, Folder 6)
- Revolution in Politics and Revolution in Literature, 1966 (Box 1310, Folder 7)
- Science and Society/The American Political System: Miracle or Anachronism?, 1967; 1968 (Box 1310, Folder 8)
- Man and the Environment: Catastrophe or Control?, 1969 (Box 1310, Folder 9)
- Man and the Environment: Catastrophe or Control?, 1969 (Box 1310, Folder 10)
- An Invitation to Versailles: The Court of Louis XIV: Absolutism on State, 1970 (Box 1310, Folder 11)
- Creativity and Crisis: Politics and Culture in Germany of the 1920s and its Meaning for Our Times, 1971 (Box 1310, Folder 12)
- A Child Goes Forth, 1972 (Box 1310, Folder 13)
- In Honor of Professor Max Salvadori: Aftermath of Empire, 1973 (Box 1310, Folder 14)
- Road Without End…The Experience of Exile, 1974 (Box 1310, Folder 15)
- Various topics, 1975-1982 (Box 1310, Folder 16)
- The Art of the Book, 1983 (Box 1310, Folder 17)
- Various topics, 1984-1989 (Box 1310, Folder 18)
- Various topics, 1991-2001 (Box 1310, Folder 19)